XINLEI DENG

SUMMARY

Accomplished **research project assistant** with 3 years of experience offering statistical analysis and expertise. Meticulously drafted scientific reports based on **clinical statistical data**. Confidently presented reports and findings to medical and scientific professionals. Worked cohesively with peers and physicians for smooth study delivery. Strong technical proficiency with work history in **biostatistics**. In-depth knowledge of **Python** and **R**. Proven history of experience in **medicine** and **statistics**.

EXPERIENCE

Research Project Assistant, 07/2019 - Current The Research Foundation of State University of New York- Albany, NY

- Worked as project coordinator for several grants.
- Used advanced analytical approaches including machine learning models to evaluate health risk factors.
- Develop spatial modeling with R, Python and ArcGIS.
- Built predictive models and deployed them as web-based tools.
- Applied interrupted time series and Bayesian spatial temporal models
- Applied Coxph, DLNM and case crossover design to solving problems in public health and clinical research.

Teaching Assistant, 05/2021 - 08/2021 The Research Foundation of State University of New York- Albany, NY

- Provided one-on-one assistance and tutoring to clinicians requiring additional help.
- Helped clinicians master learning concepts through one-on-one and small group tutoring.
- Helped professors with material generation, lesson plan development, class preparation, scheduling, exam distribution and student mentoring.

Biostatistics Scientist Intern, 01/2019 - 06/2019 Changsha Duxact Biotech Co., Ltd

- Drafted statistical sections of study protocols outlining information such as rationale, objectives, design and methodology.
- Prepared datasets using SAS.
- Prepared statistical analysis report.

Intern Doctor, 08/2018 - 01/2019 Kaiping Central Hospital - Kaiping

- Prepared patients for specific treatments.
- Updated patient records pertaining to treatment and care.
- Provided patient diagnosis, test evaluation and treatment under strict



CONTACT

Address: Albany, NY 12203 **Phone**: 518-253-2901

Email: xdeng3@albany.edu
Website: xinleideng.github.io/

SKILLS

- Python, R, SAS, ArcGIS, SPSS, SQL, Photoshop, STATA, Matlab, Graphpad
- Developed online tools: xdeng3.shinyapps.io/NIPM/ xdeng3.shinyapps.io/CHD model/

HONORS

- Served as reviewer for Indoor Air,
 BioMed Research International, &
 Health and Place journals.
- Served as moderator at the American Public Health Association (APHA) conference for Big Data Analytics for Public Health Research session.
- Served as The Nation's Health Board Representative (Chair) for APHA - Student Assembly
- Student and New Researcher Network (SNRN) Award at 2020 ISEE conference.
- The Health Research, Inc. David Axelrod Award
- Registration Award and oral presentation at 2021 ISEE

time constraints.

- Scheduled patient appointments and specific treatments.
- Facilitated patient check-ins and check-outs.

Data Management Intern, 02/2018 - 03/2018 Hunan BRI Medicine Co., Ltd. - Hunan

- Detected and resolved data quality issues and discrepancies for integrity and quality control.
- Devised reports and visualizations to present requested data in sleek format.

Intern Doctor, 09/2017 - 01/2018 Third Affiliated Hospital, Sun Yat-sen University - Guangzhou

- Updated patient records pertaining to treatment and care.
- Provided patient diagnosis, test evaluation and treatment under strict time constraints.
- Maintained awareness of advances in modern medicine, including computerized diagnostic equipment, data processing technology, sanitation protocol and life support machinery.

Intern Doctor, 09/2015 - 10/2015 Hailong Street Community Healthcare Service Center - Guangzhou

- Recorded patients' medical history, vital statistics and test results in electronic medical records.
- Facilitated patient check-ins and check-outs.

Intern Doctor, 08/2015 - 09/2015 Sixth Affiliated Hospital of Sun Yat-sen University - Guangzhou

- Prepared patients for specific treatments.
- Updated patient records pertaining to treatment and care.
- Recorded patients' medical history, vital statistics and test results in electronic medical records.

Intern Doctor, 02/2015 - 03/2015 Yiyang Central Hospital - Hunan

- Added and corrected information in patient electronic health records.
- Prepared patients for specific treatments and changed dressings .
- Monitored patients with acute conditions for changes, improvements or need for intervention.

PUBLICATIONS

- Deng X, Thurston G, Zhang W, Ryan I, Jiang C, Khwaja H, et al. Application of data science methods to identify school and home risk factors for asthma and allergy-related symptoms among children in New York. Science of the Total Environment. 2021 May 20;770.
- Zhang T, Zhang G, Deng X, Zeng J, Jin J, Zeping H, Wu M, Zheng R. APS
 (Age, Platelets, 2D Shear-Wave Elastography) Score Predicts
 Hepatocellular Carcinoma in Chronic Hepatitis B. Radiology. 2021 Aug
 24:204700. doi: 10.1148/radiol.2021204700. Epub ahead of print. PMID:
 34427463.
- Sheridan SC, Zhang W, Deng X, Lin S. The individual and synergistic impacts of windstorms and power outages on injury ED visits in New

conference.

- Oral presentation at 2021 APHA conference.
- Poster presentation at Society for Epidemiologic Research, International Society of Biometeorology

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Medicine, Preventive Medicine, 06/2019 Sun Yat-sen Univeristy - Guangzhou, China

- Thesis: Time series clustering analysis on the epidemiological characteristics of notifiable infectious diseases in China
- Outstanding Thesis Recipient
- SYSU First Class Scholarship, SYSU Jerry Yan Scholarship, Scholarship of Zhibin Yao and Xiao Tan for Excellent Medical Students Recipient
- The Third Prize of the Sixth Medical Knowledge Contest
- The Third Prize of the Sixth Medical Skills Contest

Biostatistics, 08/2020 Peking University - Beijing, China

 Completed continuing education in Biostatistics

Ph.D., Environmental Health Sciences, Expected in 12/2022 SUNY At Albany - Albany, NY

- 2021 American Public Health Association Member
- 2020 International Society for Environmental Epidemiology Member
- Full scholarship Recipient
- George Scholarship
- Travel award for conference
- Completed professional development in Biostatistics
- Completed coursework in Biostatistics, Epidemiology and Data Management
- 4.97 GPA

York State. Science of The Total Environment [Internet]. 2021 Nov [cited 2021 Jul 29];797:149199. Available from:

https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0048969721042728

- Qu Y, Zhang W, Ryan I, Deng X, Dong G, Liu X, et al. Ambient extreme heat exposure in summer and transitional months and emergency department visits and hospital admissions due to pregnancy complications. Science of the Total Environment. 2021 Jul 10;777.
- Guo J, Wu Y, Deng X, Liu Z, Chen L, Huang Y. Association between social determinants of health and direct economic burden on middle-aged and elderly individuals living with diabetes in China. PLoS ONE. 2021 Apr 1;16(4 April).
- Deng X, Zhang W, Yu F, Ryan I, Luo G, Lin S. Short-term risk effects of exposure to ultrafine particles on emergency department visits of renal diseases in New York State, 2013-2017. ISEE Conf Abstr [Internet]. 2021 Aug 23 [cited 2021 Aug 26];2021(1). Available from: https://ehp.niehs.nih.gov/doi/10.1289/isee.2021.O-TO-127
- Deng, X. L., et al. "Effects of irisin on serum lipid level in mice fed a high-fat diet." Hainan Medical Journal (2018).
- Cai Y, Gong W, He H, Hughes JP, Simoni J, Xiao S, et al. Mobile texting and lay health supporters to improve schizophrenia care in a resource-poor community in rural China (LEAN Trial): Randomized controlled trial extended implementation. Journal of Medical Internet Research. 2020 Dec 1;22(12).
- Deng X, Brotzge J, Zhang W, Ye B, Ryan I, Qu Y, et al. Assessing the
 association between meteorological factors and mental disorders in
 summer using Mesonet, a refined weather monitoring system, in New
 York State. ISEE Conference Abstracts. 2020 Oct 26;2020(1).
- E B, Zhang W, Deng X, Ryan I, Qu Y, Lin S. Impacts of environmental policies on students' test scores mediating by school attendance rate. ISEE Conference Abstracts. 2020 Oct 26;2020(1).
- Xie, L. S., Ling-Yun, W. U., Zhang, L., Deng, X. L., Guo, J. W., & Yan, Z. H., et al. (2019). Analysis of the costs and influencing factors of in-patients with liver cancer in guangzhou,2001-2016. Chinese Journal of Cancer Prevention and Treatment.
- Package "APML" An Approach for Machine-Learning Modelling [Internet]. [cited 2021 Jul 29]. Available from: https://www.researchgate.net/publication/345820172_Package_'APML'_An_Approach_for_Machine-Learning_Modelling
- Wang T, Xu D, Fan Q, Rong W, Zheng J, Gao C, et al. 1,2-Dichloroethane impairs glucose and lipid homeostasis in the livers of NIH Swiss mice. Toxicology. 2017 Apr 1;380:38–49.